<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Damage Studios | Tony Guntharp]]></title>
  <link href="http://fusion94.org//blog/categories/damage-studios/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fusion94.org//"/>
  <updated>2014-02-18T06:14:46-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://fusion94.org//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[fusion94]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[fusion94@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Damage Studios Advisory Board.]]></title>
    <link href="http://fusion94.org//blog/2002/12/10/damage-studios-advisory-board/"/>
    <updated>2002-12-10T21:47:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://fusion94.org//blog/2002/12/10/damage-studios-advisory-board</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So we&rsquo;ve announced our Board of Advisors for Damage Studios. Here&rsquo;s a copy of the press release.</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>Damage Studios Incorporated Forms Board of Advisors with Three Key Appointments</strong></p>

<p>Advisory Team to Bolster Damage&rsquo;s Capabilities with Expertise in Content, Corporate Strategy, Financial Management and Venture Capital</p>

<p>SAN FRANCISCO, Dec. 10 /PRNewswire/ &mdash; Damage Studios Incorporated, a game studio working on Rekonstruction, a next generation massively multiplayer online game, today announces the formation of its Board of Advisors with Wil Wheaton, Todd Choy and Scott Rafer as the inaugural members.</p>

<p>&ldquo;With Big Business and Hollywood beginning to invest heavily into massive multiplayer online games, an industry projected to grow to USD$2.7 billion in 2006,&rdquo; notes Tony Guntharp, Damage president &amp; CEO, &ldquo;it is invaluable to have Wil, with his knowledge of Hollywood; Todd, with his extensive financial experience; and Scott, with his venture capital track record, join us in an advisory capacity.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Todd G. Choy</strong></p>

<p>As the Chief Financial Officer at Medem, Mr. Choy oversees the accounting, finance, human resources, and administrative operations. Mr. Choy also acts as the Company&rsquo;s Assistant Secretary and Treasurer for the Board of Directors. He most recently assisted in raising three rounds of venture capital funding for planet U Inc., an Internet consumer promotions company. Previously, Mr. Choy held various Director positions at The Gap and Nestle USA. Mr. Choy is a member of the Board of Advisors of Angry Coffee Inc., a digital music firm.</p>

<p>Mr. Choy holds a Master of Business Administration in Finance from San Francisco State and a Bachelor of Science from the University of California, Berkeley.</p>

<p><strong>Scott Rafer</strong></p>

<p>Currently Mr. Rafer is the chairman of WiFinder, a wireless networking services company. Previously, Mr. Rafer was CEO of Fresher Information Corp. for which he raised over $20 million of venture capital. Other positions held by Mr. Rafer include President of FotoNation, General Manager of Internet Products and Services for Kodak and Vice President of Operations for Torque Systems. Mr. Rafer started his career in technology as an analyst at the investment bank Needham &amp; Company in New York.</p>

<p>Mr. Rafer is a graduate of the Jerome Fisher Program at the University of Pennsylvania, a double degree program jointly offered by the Wharton School of Business and the Moore School of Engineering.</p>

<p><strong>Wil Wheaton</strong></p>

<p>Wil Wheaton first entered the public eye in 1986 with his critically acclaimed performance in Rob Reiner&rsquo;s &ldquo;Stand By Me&rdquo;. He spent his teenage years on the starship Enterprise as a series regular on &ldquo;Star Trek: The Next Generation&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Wil is currently a writer and performer with the ACME Comedy Theatre, and was recently called &ldquo;rather remarkable&rdquo; by LA Weekly. Upcoming roles include the romantic lead in the dark comedy &ldquo;Jane White is Sick and Twisted&rdquo; and a guest starring lead on PAX TV&rsquo;s &ldquo;Twice In A Lifetime&rdquo;.</p>

<p><strong>About Damage Studios</strong></p>

<p>Damage Studios Incorporated is a San Francisco, CA based development studio that has been formed to create the world&rsquo;s most dynamic MMORPG: Rekonstruction&trade;. For more information, please see <a href="http://www.damagestudios.com">http://www.damagestudios.com</a> or email us at <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#x6c;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#x70;&#x72;&#x65;&#x73;&#x73;&#x40;&#100;&#97;&#x6d;&#97;&#103;&#x65;&#115;&#116;&#117;&#100;&#x69;&#111;&#115;&#x2e;&#99;&#x6f;&#109;&#46;">&#112;&#x72;&#101;&#x73;&#115;&#64;&#100;&#x61;&#109;&#x61;&#103;&#x65;&#115;&#116;&#117;&#100;&#105;&#111;&#x73;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;&#46;</a></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RPGamer: Interview with Chris DiBona]]></title>
    <link href="http://fusion94.org//blog/2002/11/08/rpgamer-interview-with-chris-dibona/"/>
    <updated>2002-11-08T21:55:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://fusion94.org//blog/2002/11/08/rpgamer-interview-with-chris-dibona</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>RPGamer has an interview with one of the Damage Studios co-founders that talks about the studio and the game. You can rad the interview <a href="http://www.rpgamer.com/features/rekoninterview/rekoninterview.html">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
