<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Science | fusion94]]></title>
  <link href="http://fusion94.org//blog/categories/science/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fusion94.org//"/>
  <updated>2014-02-13T17:34:03-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://fusion94.org//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[fusion94]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[California Academy of Sciences Trip]]></title>
    <link href="http://fusion94.org//blog/2002/03/16/california-academy-of-sciences-trip/"/>
    <updated>2002-03-16T14:01:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://fusion94.org//blog/2002/03/16/california-academy-of-sciences-trip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I spent about 3 &frac12; hours at the <a href="http://www.calacademy.org/">California Academy of Sciences</a> today. I spent most of my time in the Natural History Museum and the Steinhart Aquarium. Saw several very cool exhibits.</p>

<p>The Department of Ichthyology had an exhibit where they had x-rayed several types and species of fish. It was way cool and wasn`t expected.</p>

<p>The Steinhart Aquarium also had several cool things. One of which was the display of Burmese Vine Snakes. The aquarium was the first in the world to display these snakes. These snakes are rear fanged and venomous although their venom isn`t that dangerous to humans. They are also unique in the fact that while they are Vine/Tree Dwelling snakes they primarily eat fish and hunt from low hanging vines and limbs. It was interesting watching them hunt.</p>

<p>The Aquarium had several other snakes that were interesting to view. They had 2 Gaboon Vipers from Africa on display. It was the first time I had seen the Gaboon up close and they are very beautiful snakes.</p>

<p>Gaboons can reach a length of 4 feet on average, but lengths of 7 feet and more have been recorded. These animals will weigh about 8 to 10 kg and have a head-size of approximately 5 inches and matching fangs of 2 inches. Gaboons are the largest of the Vipers and is one of three members of the African Giant Vipers Group.</p>

<p>All in all it was a great day. I can<code>t believe that I</code>ve lived here in the Bay Area for 6 years now and just got around to visiting the Academy. If you visit San Francisco or live in the area and are interested in Reptiles I highly recommend visiting the Academy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
