<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Zend Studio | fusion94]]></title>
  <link href="http://fusion94.github.io/blog/categories/zend-studio/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fusion94.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-12T18:30:32-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://fusion94.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[fusion94]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANT and Zend Studio]]></title>
    <link href="http://fusion94.github.io/blog/2009/01/12/ant-and-zend-studio/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-12T08:25:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://fusion94.github.io/blog/2009/01/12/ant-and-zend-studio</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Zend Studio for Eclipse is a commercial edition of Eclipse plus the PDT plugin and various other additions. Unfortunately Zend decided to disable the Ant plugin in it&rsquo;s distribution of the Eclipse platform. Nonetheless if you&rsquo;d like to run Ant scripts or simple Phing scripts it would be really useful to be able to use the Ant integration of Eclipse.</p>

<p><b>Preparation</b>
First you need to make sure that the Eclipse Java Development Tools are available in Zend Studio for Eclipse.</p>

<ul> 
<li>From the Help menu click Software Updates > Manage Configuration. 
<li>Check for the entry Eclipse Java Development Tools. 
</ul>


<p>If the entry is not listed or disabled, you need to install the Eclipse feature.</p>

<ul>
<li>From the Help menu click Software Updates > Find and Install. 
<li>Click Search for new features to install. 
<li>Check Europa Discovery Site and click Next. 
<li>Select Java Development Tools and click Finish to install the feature. 
<li>Restart Zend Studio for Eclipse. 
</ul>


<p><b>How to enable the Ant integration</b>
Now it gets a little tricky.</p>

<ul>
<li>From the File menu click New > Project. 
<li>Check Show All Wizards. 
<img src="http://fusion94.github.io/images/zend-ant/1.jpg">
<li>In the Wizards text field enter Ant, select Java Project from Existing Ant Buildfile and click Next. 
<img src="http://fusion94.github.io/images/zend-ant/2.jpg">
<li>You will be asked to enable Ant Development - confirm with Yes. 
<img src="http://fusion94.github.io/images/zend-ant/3.jpg">
<li>Now you can cancel the new Java Project - Ant has been activated. 
</ul>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
