<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: OpenROV | Tony Guntharp]]></title>
  <link href="http://fusion94.org/blog/categories/openrov/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fusion94.org/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-21T12:54:32-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://fusion94.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[fusion94]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[fusion94@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenROV Build Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://fusion94.org/blog/2013/01/13/openrov-build-day/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-13T05:46:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://fusion94.org/blog/2013/01/13/openrov-build-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;re glad to hear that many of the kits made it under the Christmas tree! Now, the next phase: building them!
<img class="right" src="/images/blog/openrov/openrov_icon.jpeg" width="120" height="120">
The <a href="http://wiki.openrov.com">OpenROV Wiki</a> is really starting to fill out: <a href="http://wiki.openrov.com/index.php/Assembly#Step_by_step_instructions">Step by Step Instructions</a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s the best place to start. The goal is for each section of the build to have:</p>

<!-- more -->


<ol>
<li>Tools/Materials/Parts</li>
<li>Video/Photos/Explanation</li>
<li>Test (to make sure it works and you don&rsquo;t move on until it&rsquo;s functioning correctly)</li>
<li>Troubleshooting</li>
</ol>


<p>The endcap process is a good example of what we are striving for: <a href="http://wiki.openrov.com/index.php/Assembling_and_Gluing_the_end_caps">Endcap Assembly</a></p>

<p>The most important thing to remember: the OpenROV is a work-in-progress. If you have a question, or a doubt, or an idea: SPEAK UP! The only way this project gets better is if it continues to be tweaked and improved by everyone who works on it. If you think you&rsquo;ve got a better way of explaining something &ndash; let&rsquo;s discuss it!</p>

<p>Also, we&rsquo;re planning on hosting build days at our small office in Berkeley. We&rsquo;ll be streaming the build days from our new <a href="https://plus.google.com/u/1/communities/116561282178440599596">OpenROV Community page on G+</a> so anyone around the world can tune in and ask questions (all videos will be archived on Youtube).</p>

<p>The first build day &ndash; the acrylic structure &ndash; will be on Saturday, January 19th starting at 12pm PST.</p>

<p>If you want to join us in-person in Berkeley, please send David Lang an email at: david @ openrov.com</p>

<h4>Details</h4>

<p>Saturday, January 19, 2013 from 12pm to whenever (PST)</p>

<p>OpenROV HQ<br>
614 Bancroft Way &ndash; Suite C<br>
Berkeley CA<br></p>

<p><strong>What to Bring</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Your OpenROV kits</li>
<li>A Camera</li>
<li>Laptop</li>
<li>Willingness to help</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>What is OpenROV</strong></p>

<p>OpenROV is a  Do It Yourself telerobotics community centered around underwater exploration and education. We have developed a low-cost telerobotic submarine that can be built with mostly off-the-shelf parts. The goal of OpenROV is to democratize exploration by allowing anyone to explore and study underwater environments.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a short video of it in action.
<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/44088059 "></iframe></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BeagleBone + Webcam Holder for OpenROV]]></title>
    <link href="http://fusion94.org/blog/2012/11/26/beaglebone-plus-webcam-holder-for-openrov/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-26T19:49:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://fusion94.org/blog/2012/11/26/beaglebone-plus-webcam-holder-for-openrov</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I&rsquo;ve been working with the <a href="http://beagleboard.org/bone">BeagleBone</a> linux computer as part
of the OpenROV project I was getting frustrated with the lack of stands/mounting brackets out
there to secure the BeagleBone.</p>

<p>I searched <a href="http://thingiverse.com/">Thingiverse</a> and located the <a href="http://www.thingiverse.com/thing:30537">BeagleBone + Webcam holder</a>.
I tried to print this on my Prusa and while it came out more or less all right the angled overhang
was really sloppy. This version also uses printed stand up pins to secure the BeagleBone and a
latching system that wasn&rsquo;t completely compatible with the use of a <a href="http://beagleboard.org/cape">BeagleBone Cape</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><strong>Version One (V1)</strong></p>

<p>So I redesigned the original part in SketchUp and made it boxier without the overhang. This
produced a totally usable product although it took 2.5 hours to print and still suffered from
the issue of not properly securing the BeagleBone.</p>

<p>Here is a photo of Version One:</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/openrov/openrov_holder_v1.jpg"></p>

<p><strong>Version Two (V2)</strong></p>

<p>In talking with this further with <a href="http://toddsampson.com/">Todd Sampson</a> we decided to reduce
the mass of the model as well as removed the stand up pins used to secure the BeagleBone and
replaced them with 3mm holes so that the BeagleBone could be properly secured to the holder.
Version Two also takes less than 40 minutes to print.</p>

<p>Here is a photo of Version Two:</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/openrov/openrov_holder_v2.jpg"></p>

<p>In the end either stand is perfect for working with the OpenROV BeagleBone and OpenROV Cape. It is suitable for sitting on your desk, or for mounting to a wall. You can download everything related to it at:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.thingiverse.com/thing:34886">Thingiverse</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/fusion94/BeagleBoneHolder-OpenROV">Github</a></li>
</ul>


<p>To learn more about the OpenROV Project head over to the <a href="http://openrov.com/">OpenROV</a> website.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenRov #1]]></title>
    <link href="http://fusion94.org/blog/2012/08/21/openrov-number-1/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-21T21:01:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://fusion94.org/blog/2012/08/21/openrov-number-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was visiting David and Eric over at the Rainbow Mansion not too long and was able to
snag a couple of photos of the first OpenROV design. This is Serial #001.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/openrov/openrov001_1.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/openrov/openrov001_2.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
