<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Legacy | Tony Guntharp]]></title>
  <link href="http://fusion94.org/blog/categories/legacy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fusion94.org/"/>
  <updated>2015-09-09T12:31:26-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://fusion94.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[fusion94]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[fusion94@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Son...and a Legacy]]></title>
    <link href="http://fusion94.org/blog/2014/02/27/my-son-dot-dot-dot-and-a-legacy/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-27T18:44:59-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://fusion94.org/blog/2014/02/27/my-son-dot-dot-dot-and-a-legacy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post will be a little different than most of my posts. I&rsquo;d like to talk a bit about my son (Patrick, named after my mother, Patricia, who died of cancer in 2003) and a Legacy<sup id='fnref:1'><a href='#fn:1' rel='footnote'>[1]</a></sup> that my son will hear about but hopefully will not abide<sup id='fnref:2'><a href='#fn:2' rel='footnote'>[2]</a></sup> by.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My son turned 14 months old today. I was 43 years old when he was born. It was absolutely the best moment of my life. Nothing can ever compare to seeing him for the first time or holding him just moments after he left the womb. It left me awestruck and amazed.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/legacy/pg1.jpg"></p>

<p>I will do anything to protect him. If anyone tried to harm him I would absolutely destroy them and their existence from this planet. No question. I would willingly give up my life for his in an instant.</p>

<h3>The Legacy</h3>

<p>Now many of you will now be asking <em>&ldquo;What is this legacy?&rdquo;</em> Well it&rsquo;s the legacy of the Combat Infantryman&rsquo;s Badge (hereafter referred to as the CIB). Yes I have one, as does Patrick&rsquo;s Grandfather and his Great-Grandfather.</p>

<p>Now you may be asking yourself: <em>&ldquo;What is the CIB?&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/legacy/cib.gif"></p>

<blockquote><p>The <strong>Combat Infantryman Badge (CIB)</strong> is a United States Army military award. The badge is awarded to infantrymen and Special Forces Soldiers in the rank of Colonel and below, who personally fought in active ground combat while assigned as members of either an infantry, Ranger or Special Forces unit, of brigade size or smaller, any time after 6 December 1941.</p>

<p>The CIB and its non-combat contemporary, the Expert Infantryman Badge (EIB) were simultaneously created during World War II to enhance the morale and prestige of service in the infantry. Specifically, it recognizes the <strong>inherent sacrifices of all infantrymen</strong>, and that, in comparison to all other military occupational specialties, infantrymen face the greatest risk of being <strong>wounded or killed in action</strong>.</p></blockquote>

<p>Patrick&rsquo;s Great-Grandfather earned his CIB during World War II fighting with the 69th Infantry Division comprising of (3) Infantry regiments of 3,254 men that fought in places such as the Battle of the Bulge (26-Dec-1944), Attacking the Siegfried Line (27-Feb-1945), Battle for Kassel (05-Apr-1945), Battle for Leipzig (18-Apr-1945), and the Linkup with the Soviet 58th Guards in Berlin (25-Apr-1945).</p>

<p>Patrick&rsquo;s Grandfather earned his CIB while on the Korean DMZ from 1969-1970 with the 2nd Infantry Division.</p>

<p>Patrick&rsquo;s Father earned his CIB while attached to 18th Airborne Corps during Operation Desert Shield/Desert Storm.</p>

<p>My Grandfather (Patrick&rsquo;s Great-Grandfather) pinned on me the <strong>CIB</strong> that he earned during WWII. Not a replica, the actual <strong>CIB</strong> that was awarded to him in 1945. It was absolutely one of the finest moments of my life.</p>

<p>It is an honor that&rsquo;s difficult to describe. I have never been as proud as I was that day. At that moment I became part of a brotherhood that was far bigger than myself. A brotherhood that was a legacy and a huge cross to bear.</p>

<p>Up until that point, my grandfather hadn&rsquo;t really spoken of his time in service. After that day he opened up to me in ways that I never knew existed. We spoke at length in regards to what we had experienced and found common ground. While serving almost 50 years apart we shared the same experiences and both suffered from what now is referred to as PTSD (Shell Shock in his day).</p>

<p>It was difficult for my Grandfather to open up, less difficult to open up to me as we had both faced the elephant in the room for better or for worse.</p>

<h3>A New Beginning</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m not planning on telling Patrick about the <strong>CIB</strong>, having said that neither will I lie about it.</p>

<p>I hope to God that in the future he will never have the opportunity to
experience his family&rsquo;s legacy. I desperately hope that my son never has to go to war or see combat in any way, shape, form or fashion.</p>

<p><strong>This will be my legacy to him.</strong></p>

<p><div class="footnotes">
	<ol>
		<li id='fn:1'><p> anything handed down from the past, as from an ancestor or predecessor.
  <a href='#fnref:1' rev='footnote'>↩</a></p>
</li><li id='fn:2'><p> accept or act in accordance with (a rule, decision, or recommendation).
<a href='#fnref:2' rev='footnote'>↩</a></p>
</li>
	</ol>
</div>
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
