<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tumblr | Tony Guntharp]]></title>
  <link href="http://fusion94.org/blog/categories/tumblr/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fusion94.org/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-01T06:11:02-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://fusion94.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[fusion94]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[fusion94@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bye-Bye Tumblr, Hello Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://fusion94.org/blog/2013/01/05/bye-bye-tumblr/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-05T14:27:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://fusion94.org/blog/2013/01/05/bye-bye-tumblr</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my first post published using <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> after several years of using either <a href="http://drupal.org">Drupal</a> and/or <a href="http://tumblr.com">tumblr</a> and I’d like to share the reasons why I chose to move from a blogging platform and switch to a statically generated site.</p>

<p>Yes, because what you are reading is pure static old-school HTML, generated by Octopress on my MacBook Pro. Also to note is that everything here is being served by GitHub through the Pages feature, completely free.</p>

<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>Octopress sports a clean responsive theme written in semantic HTML5, focused on readability and friendliness toward mobile devices.</li>
<li>Code blogging is easy and beautiful. Embed code (with Solarized styling) in your posts from gists, jsFiddle or from your filesystem.</li>
<li>Third party integration is simple with built-in support for Twitter, Pinboard, Delicious, GitHub Repositories, Disqus Comments and Google Analytics.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s easy to use. A collection of rake tasks simplifies development and makes deploying a cinch.</li>
<li>Ships with great plug-ins some original and others from the Jekyll community — tested and improved.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Ease of Use</h3>

<p><a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> is a framework built upon <a href="http://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a>, the Ruby static site generator that powers GitHub Pages.</p>

<p>Jekyll takes a content directory, parses all the articles and pages through a Markdown converter and generates a static website that can be served with almost anything.</p>

<p>Octopress leverages all the power of Jekyll adding a great HTML5 template, mobile ready, and a lot of features like archives, an xml sitemap, code highlighting, external services integration (Twitter, Github, Google+, Facebook), and much much more.</p>

<p>This solution makes your website really fast because there’s no dynamic code that runs on the server and no databases.</p>

<h3>3rd Party Plugins</h3>

<p>Octopress has a wealth of <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/wiki/3rd-party-plugins">3rd Party Plugins</a> that will allow you to do most anything you want to do.</p>

<h3>Themes</h3>

<p>Octopress also has quite a few <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/wiki/3rd-Party-Octopress-Themes">3rd Party Themes</a> for you to use and to customize.</p>

<h3>Open Source</h3>

<p>Best of all is that Octopress is Open Source and licensed under The MIT License.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
